<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Open Source on</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/categories/open-source/</link><description>Recent content in Open Source on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 05:10:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pavithraes.me/categories/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Beginner's Guide to Communication in FOSS</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/beginners-guide-to-communication-in-foss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 05:10:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/beginners-guide-to-communication-in-foss/</guid><description>Free and Open Source software is maintained by people working remotely from around the world. Hence, effective communication is important for any project to function smoothly.
Especially, asynchronous-written communication.
I started contributing to FOSS over a year ago. Communication was one of the first things I had to learn. I&amp;rsquo;m still working on it, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way. Here are some key points I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up.</description></item><item><title>Season of Docs - And... it's over</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-and...-its-over/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 20:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-and...-its-over/</guid><description>I like working with the Wikimedia community. I got to interact with some really amazing folks and the overall experience has been wonderful! Even though Season of Docs has officially come to an end, I intend to continue contributing and would welcome interested folks to join us.
Outreachy-19 # I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest here. The best part of working with The Wikimedia Foundation was helping the Outreachy applicants. I absolutely loved it!</description></item><item><title>Season of Docs - Community Bonding and Doc-Development</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-community-bonding-and-doc-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 14:10:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-community-bonding-and-doc-development/</guid><description>My mentor is awesome. Setting expectations early is important. A large portion of technical writing is research. I got the acceptance email! I was sooo excited and couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to get started!
Special note: Sarah R. Rodlund was my GSoD mentor, and she is awesome. She is super knowledgeable, kind, supportive, patient and encouraging. Genuinely. The best part, she always spreads happy energy. I came out of every meeting feeling cheerful, energized and motivated to do more.</description></item><item><title>Season of Docs - Application</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-application/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 11:33:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-application/</guid><description>Persistence is sometimes more important than skill. Jumping into the deep end is probably not a good idea? We regret the shots we don’t take. There are opportunities out there! For women, for everyone, we just need to reach out. Some tips on writing good proposals. I was introduced to open source software and Outreachy in early December of 2018. For those unfamiliar with Outreachy, it is an open-source initiative that provides internships in FOSS for under-represented folks in tech.</description></item></channel></rss>