<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Documentation on</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/categories/documentation/</link><description>Recent content in Documentation on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 19:30:00 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pavithraes.me/categories/documentation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Plain English for Everyone</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/plain-english-for-everyone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 19:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/plain-english-for-everyone/</guid><description>Plain English is clear and concise English.
Technical writing is different from creative writing. The goal of technical documentation is to make complex technical information easy to understand. Hence, Plain English is an important aspect of technical writing. It makes your document more accessible, consistent, and readable.
Why Plain English? # English is not the first language for many people. More people can understand Plain English compared to sophisticated English.</description></item><item><title>Season of Docs - And... it's over</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-and...-its-over/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 20:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-and...-its-over/</guid><description>👉 This post was written in 2019. It is likely quite outdated, and may not reflect my current thoughts and beliefs. :) I like working with the Wikimedia community. I got to interact with some really amazing folks and the overall experience has been wonderful! Even though Season of Docs has officially come to an end, I intend to continue contributing and would welcome interested folks to join us.</description></item><item><title>Season of Docs - Community Bonding and Doc-Development</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-community-bonding-and-doc-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 14:10:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-community-bonding-and-doc-development/</guid><description>👉 This post was written in 2019. It is likely quite outdated, and may not reflect my current thoughts and beliefs. :) My mentor is awesome. Setting expectations early is important. A large portion of technical writing is research. I got the acceptance email! I was sooo excited and couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to get started!
Special note: Sarah R. Rodlund was my GSoD mentor, and she is awesome. She is super knowledgeable, kind, supportive, patient and encouraging.</description></item><item><title>Season of Docs - Application</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-application/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 11:33:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-application/</guid><description>👉 This post was written in 2019. It is likely quite outdated, and may not reflect my current thoughts and beliefs. :) Persistence is sometimes more important than skill. Jumping into the deep end is probably not a good idea? We regret the shots we don’t take. There are opportunities out there! For women, for everyone, we just need to reach out. Some tips on writing good proposals. I was introduced to open source software and Outreachy in early December of 2018.</description></item></channel></rss>