<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pavithra Eswaramoorthy on</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/contributors/pavithra-eswaramoorthy/</link><description>Recent content in Pavithra Eswaramoorthy on</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 20:39:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pavithraes.me/contributors/pavithra-eswaramoorthy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bullet Journaling - My Setup</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/bullet-journaling-my-setup/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 20:39:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/bullet-journaling-my-setup/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been bullet journaling for almost 2 years. This feels amazing to say because no other planning/organising system has worked for me for more than few weeks me. So, in this quick post, I want to share why I love bullet journaling and what my personal setup looks like.
Wait a minute, what is bullet journaling? # In a nutshell, it is using a plain old paper notebook as your planner with one main rule: maintain an index.</description></item><item><title>Beginner's Guide to Communication in FOSS</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/beginners-guide-to-communication-in-foss/</link><pubDate>Sun, 18 Oct 2020 05:10:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/beginners-guide-to-communication-in-foss/</guid><description>Free and Open Source software is maintained by people working remotely from around the world. Hence, effective communication is important for any project to function smoothly.
Especially, asynchronous-written communication.
I started contributing to FOSS over a year ago. Communication was one of the first things I had to learn. I&amp;rsquo;m still working on it, but I think I&amp;rsquo;ve come a long way. Here are some key points I&amp;rsquo;ve picked up.</description></item><item><title>Plain English for Everyone</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/plain-english-for-everyone/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 19:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/plain-english-for-everyone/</guid><description>Plain English is clear and concise English.
Technical writing is different from creative writing. The goal of technical documentation is to make complex technical information easy to understand. Hence, Plain English is an important aspect of technical writing. It makes your document more accessible, consistent, and readable.
Why Plain English? # English is not the first language for many people. More people can understand Plain English compared to sophisticated English.</description></item><item><title>Data Visualization Introduction</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/data-visualization-introduction/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 17:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/data-visualization-introduction/</guid><description>Preface # I started planning this series to share my data visualization lecture notes. But, over the past week, it has turned into something much bigger. As I learn more about data visualization, I realized there&amp;rsquo;s more I want to share.
This is not intended as a tutorial or a comprehensive guide. It is just me sharing some notes and thoughts and hoping you find it useful.
What is Data Visualization?</description></item><item><title>Top Books - 2020</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/top-books-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 02:35:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/top-books-2020/</guid><description>One of my resolutions for 2020 is to read regularly. Reading, especially reading books, helps me stay centred. I find it meditative and the hours count towards my &amp;ldquo;me time&amp;rdquo;.
I&amp;rsquo;ve read some really good books so far this year, I want to share them here.
Becoming by Michelle Obama # This book made waves when it was released. It is definitely one of the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far.</description></item><item><title>The Moment of Lift - Book Review</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/the-moment-of-lift-book-review/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Aug 2020 01:30:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/the-moment-of-lift-book-review/</guid><description>You can buy it here.
CW: book talks about discrimination and violence against women.
This is a very powerful book by Melinda Gates. The title, &amp;ldquo;How empowering women can change the world&amp;rdquo; communicates the goal of this book effectively. Definitely one of the best books I&amp;rsquo;ve read so far. :)
I started reading it because I was curious. Bill and Melinda Gates are obviously popular public figures. I had read their annual letter and passively followed the news around their philanthropic work, but I was not prepared for how impactful this book would be.</description></item><item><title>Importing Blogs to Medium</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/importing-blogs-to-medium/</link><pubDate>Mon, 06 Jul 2020 23:00:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/importing-blogs-to-medium/</guid><description>Bokeh recently decided to move it&amp;rsquo;s blog, hosted at https://blog.bokeh.org/, to the popular publishing platform Medium. This comes with a set of advantages and disadvantages, but we won&amp;rsquo;t go there today. The decision was taken after careful consideration and after listening to both sides of the debate. Let&amp;rsquo;s leave it at that.
Here is my overall experience moving old posts to Medium. If you plan on doing this sometime, my learnings here might be helpful.</description></item><item><title>What Got You Here Won't Get You There - Book Summary</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/what-got-you-here-wont-get-you-there-book-summary/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 11:20:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/what-got-you-here-wont-get-you-there-book-summary/</guid><description>A book by Marshall Goldsmith, you can buy it here. :)
The Trouble With Success # Oftentimes, our previous success prevents us from achieving more. People who tend to be very successful sometimes do not realize how their behaviour is coming across to other people. These super successful people have some bad habits. They need to realize that they are successful, not because of their bad habits, but in spite of it.</description></item><item><title>Season of Docs - And... it's over</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-and...-its-over/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 20:55:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-and...-its-over/</guid><description>❗️ This post was written in 2019. It is likely quite outdated, and may not reflect my current thoughts and beliefs. I like working with the Wikimedia community. I got to interact with some really amazing folks and the overall experience has been wonderful! Even though Season of Docs has officially come to an end, I intend to continue contributing and would welcome interested folks to join us.
Outreachy-19 # I&amp;rsquo;ll be honest here.</description></item><item><title>Season of Docs - Community Bonding and Doc-Development</title><link>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-community-bonding-and-doc-development/</link><pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2019 14:10:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pavithraes.me/blog/season-of-docs-community-bonding-and-doc-development/</guid><description>❗️ This post was written in 2019. It is likely quite outdated, and may not reflect my current thoughts and beliefs. My mentor is awesome. Setting expectations early is important. A large portion of technical writing is research. I got the acceptance email! I was sooo excited and couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to get started!
Special note: Sarah R. Rodlund was my GSoD mentor, and she is awesome. She is super knowledgeable, kind, supportive, patient and encouraging.</description></item></channel></rss>